

Zahra Noor

Web Developer 39 West Lexington Street 803, Baltimore, MD, 21201 (443) 653-7320

E-mail: zahranoorwd@gmail.com Portfolio: Click Here

Career Summary

Front End Web Developer with first hand experience of multi-platform responsive, accessible, usable and adaptive web-design. Experience with Front End (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX); Back End (SQL, PHP, AngularJS); Content Management Systems (Wordpress, Drupal, Placester, Squarespace) and Design Softwares (Adobe CC). Open to full-time challenging roles, that will allow me to showcase my abilities while also enhancing or building great websites.

Professional Experience

American Institutes For Research (AIR), Washington, D.C. December 2017 – Present Web Designer I

- Responsible for ensuring compliance with WCAG 2.1, WAI-ARIA, HTML5 and web standards to make sure that all the components are accessible by making them perceivable, operable, understandable and robust.
- Developed a style guide toolkit using fabricator for accessibility developers to reduce overhead due to repetition and complexity.
- Increasing accessibility in AIR assessment and testing products to ensure a user-friendly experience for people with disabilities.
- Collaborating with teams in order to conduct function-based brainstorming for chalking out innovative ways to resolve accessibility bugs.
- Active reviewing of websites created by other colleagues and giving feedback for accessibility compliance, usability, design and functionality.
- Developing demonstrative website mockups using Photoshop.

Real Living At Home (RLAH), Washington, D.C. Web Developer

August 2017 – November 2017

- Developing real estate websites to provide agents a platform for displaying their home listings, branding themselves as realtors and providing different home search criteria depending on min and max prices, number of beds and baths, acres and a couple of more factors in websites which make house hunting easy for their customers.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Wordpress, Bootstrap, IDX Broker and Placester.
- Converting wireframes into Web Pages.
- Increasing responsiveness of webpages using Bootstrap.
- Testing site functionality and resolving bugs.
- Integrating IDX Broker in real estate websites.
- Customizing websites according to agents needs.
- Capitol Luxury Homes (Wordpress, IDX Broker) Website 1
- Capitol Luxury Homes (Placester, IDX) Website 2
- THINKTANCK (Placester, IDX Broker) Website 3

DataNext Corporation Ltd, Naha, Okinawa. Japan Junior Web Developer

 $June\ 2016-March\ 2017$

- Developing a web-based application as a real-time aid for product delivery staff to generate reports and for managers to monitor delivery schedule, delivery location, work efficiency etc. using Laravel MVC as the framework. The application included additional features for delivery staff to make their delivery schedule, routing and sorting more easy.
- Used geolocation API for user localization.

- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, AngularJS and AJAX to create Web-based applications.
- Converting mock-ups into HTML and CSS.
- Increasing responsiveness of web pages using bootstrap (across mobile and desktop browsers).
- Analyzing software usability and performance, recommending changes to improve functionality.
- Testing site functionality and identifying problems.
- Feedback oriented interdepartmental collaborations and teamwork.
- Video with more details of the core project: Click Here

Microsoft Innovation Center (MIC), Lahore

Summer 2014

Development Intern

• Developing Natural Language Processing applications for windows based systems using C#

Lahore University of Management Science(LUMS), Lahore

Summer 2013

Research Intern

• Support Vector Machine based Algorithms for outliers detection from real-time data

Technical Skills

Programming Languages and Softwares: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS, Python, SQL

Other Tools: Laravel, Wordpress, Placester, IDX Broker, Heroku, Squarespace, Navicat for MySQL, GitHub, T_FX, MATLAB

Education

Lahore College for Women University(LCWU), Lahore

2010 - 2014

B.S. Computer Science

(CS Major GPA 3.6/4.0)

- Senior Year Project: Idea Market: An Android based ideation system (CGPA 3.48/4.0)
- Major Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Human Computer Interaction, Computer Graphics, Operating Systems (Total Credit Hours: 132)

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences, Lahore

2014 - 2015

Post Graduate Coursework

• Major Courses: Computational Intelligence, Data Mining, Statistical Pattern Recognition, Machine Learning, Applied Programming

Continuing Education

Coursera: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for Web Developers (JHU)

Udacity: Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree Program (Course in Progress)

Deep Learning: Using Pytorch for training Generative Adversarial Networks for Image-to-Image translation.

Work Authorization References

Eligible to work in the United States.

• Mr. Justin Levitch,

President, Real Living At Home (RLAH), Washington D.C

E-mail: justin@rlahre.com Cell: (469) 831-8021

• Mr. Higa Satoshi,

Technical Leader, DataNext Corporation Ltd., Japan E-mail: s.higa@datanext.co.jp

z man simga statamentico.

• Mr. Tran Minh Nhut,

Senior Web Developer, DataNext Corporation Ltd., Japan

E-mail: minhnhut 37@gmail.com

• Dr. Nauman Shahid,

Staff Scientist, United Technologies Research Center (UTRC), Ireland

E-mail: nauman.shahid@epfl.ch

• Mr. Shahid Aziz,

Technical Manager, Microsoft Innovation Center, Lahore

E-mail: v-musha@microsoft.com